RAJEEV POKHREL



No. 955, Saraswati Vihar, MG Road, Gurgaon, Haryana-122002 / Mobile: 9650330309 | Email: rajeevpokharel@gmail.com

Personal Profile

A Chartered Accountant with 11+ years of experience (5+ years in ERP field – Oracle Finance Consultant and Oracle Project Manager and balance 6+ years in Finance Domain carrying out audit and accounting of various corporate entities). Audit includes Risk Based Internal Audit, System Controls Audit, IS Audit, Concurrent, Internal and Statutory Audit of Banking, Corporate and Financial Institutions.

Have worked on 11i, 12.1.1, 12.1.3, 12.2.2 & 12.2.6 versions of Oracle including **Oracle Fusion 11.1**. Experienced in modules such as **AP**, **AR**, **GL**, **FA**, **CE**, **PA**, **AGIS**, **EB Tax**, **India Localization including GST** and having basic idea about **PO**, **INV** and **OM**. Knowledge and working experience in Oracle development tools and languages including **TOAD** and **Data Loader**.

Synopsis of Oracle Experience

- Over 5+ years of experience with Strong Functional knowledge in Implementation, Up-gradation, Support, Rollout of Oracle Financials Applications 11i & R12 (recent being 12.2.6).
- Fusion Implementation and Post Implementation support.
- Have worked on single and multi orgs organizational structure and have extensive experience in business processes evaluation, process flow development and configuration.
- Extensively Worked on Accounts Payable, Accounts Receivable, General Ledger, Fixed Assets, Cash Management,
 AGIS, EB Tax and India Localization. Also having basic knowledge of Purchasing, Project Accounting, Inventory and
 Order Management Modules.
- Sound knowledge on System Study, Business Process Modeling and Functional Design.
- Participated in Business Process Analysis, Requirement Analysis, GAP Analysis and System design.
- Involved in preparation of BP80, MD50, BR100 and User Manuals.
- Good at Handling CRPs and UATs Sessions.
- Coordinated with the sales team for Pre-Sales activity for R12 (presentation on the features, differences with 11i among others).
- Good in Project Management and Leadership Skills.

Education / Certifications

•	Chartered Accountant – The Institute of Chartered Accountants of India	Nov'12
•	Bachelors of Commerce (B.Com - Commerce) - University of Madras, Chennai	Nov'10
•	Company Secretary – The Institute of Company Secretaries of India (Final)	JUN'18

Professional Experience

•	Wipro Ltd. – Development Team Lead (B and B3)	Oct 2016 – PRESENT
•	Chain Sys (India) Pvt. Ltd. – Project Manager	July 2013 – SEP 2016
•	C.J. Sriram – Proprietorship Concern - Manager Audit & ERP Consulting	July 2010 – July 2013
•	Atul Kulshrestha & Co., Chartered Accountants – Team Lead	Jan 2007 – July 2010

Synopsis of Domain Experience

- Companies and other non-corporate entities
 - ✓ Risk based Internal Audit
 - ✓ System Controls Audit
 - ✓ Management accounting & reporting
 - ✓ Process control review, design and implementation
 - ✓ Accounting and financial analysis
 - ✓ Statutory audit and compliances

Banking Institutions

- ✓ Concurrent Audit, Internal Audit and Statutory Audit
- Audit of processes, compliances and documentations in relation to loan disbursement to High Value Corporate
 Borrowers
- ✓ ATM Audit and Credit Card Audit
- ✓ Revenue Audit and Stock Audit
- ✓ Information System (IS) Audit

Key Profile & Career highlights:

• System/ Internal Controls Audit: Aided in development / revamp of system process for various functional areas and establishment of internal control mechanism in some of the operational areas for service sectors and manufacturing units.

Tasks include:

- ✓ High Level Systems Architecture Review
- ✓ Application Security Controls
- ✓ Business Process Mapping (e.g. determining information systems dependency with respect to user business processes)
- ✓ End User Identity Management (e.g. authentication mechanisms, roles limiting or granting systems functionality)
- ✓ Logging and auditing systems and processes

• Risk Assessment and Internal Controls:

- ✓ Preparing the Internal Control Questionnaires (ICQ)
- ✓ Testing the samples and determining the adequacy of the internal controls in place
- ✓ Assessment of risks based on control matrix.
- **Concurrent & Internal Audit:** Conducted the audit of various functional areas for leading public and private sector banks (Areas Loan disbursement, Deposit acceptance, Opening of various bank accounts, Revenue leakage)

Tasks include:

- ✓ Ensuring compliances of sanctioned terms and conditions for loan disbursement
- ✓ Analysis of various ratios (Working Capital, Current Ratios etc.) of borrowers to ensure loan has been rightly disbursed
- ✓ Analysis of debtors ageing and stocks from the debtors' stock statement and review of drawing power calculated
- ✓ Ensuring that the installments of the loan are paid on timely basis and that the account has not become an NPA
- ✓ Cross verification of borrower with the RBI's defaulters list and ensuring KYC Compliances
- ✓ Ensuring the compliances of KYC norms for opening of the bank accounts

• Management & Internal Audit: Part of the audit team in conducting audit in various functional areas for leading service sectors & manufacturing companies (Areas – Accounts, Banking, Purchases, Sales, Production, Business Operations and HR, Commercial & Legal compliances).

Tasks include:

- ✓ Streamlining the existing Standard Operating Procedures (SOP)
- ✓ Analysis and verification of financial statements debtors/creditors ageing, balance confirmation procedures
- ✓ Calculation and analysis of trends and variances
- ✓ Preparation & review of various reconciliation statements such as Bank, Stock etc.

Key Oracle Engagements

Oracle Product	Product Version	Project Type	Role	Client
Oracle Fusion	11.1	Implementation & Support	Finance Consultant	Religare Health Trust
	12.1	Support	Manager cum Team Lead and Finance Consultant	Concorde Motors
	11i	Off Shore Support	Finance Consultant	Del Monte Foods
	11i	Upgrade from 11i to R12	Finance Consultant	Maruti Suzuki India Ltd.
	12.1.3	Implementation	Finance Consultant	Craftsman Automation Pvt. Ltd. Chemfab Alkalis Limited (CAL) Gates India Pvt. Ltd.
	12.1	OU Rollout	Finance Consultant	Honda Cars India Limited
Oracle EBS	12.1	OU Rollout	Finance Consultant	JTEKT Sona Automotive Ltd.
Oracic LB3	12.3	Support	Finance Consultant	Honda Motors India Pvt. Ltd.
	12.3	Support	Project Manager	Su-Kam Power Systems Ltd.
	12.2	Financial Consolidation	Project Manager	Sandhar Technologies Ltd.
	12.1	Support Upgrade from 12.1 to R12.3	Finance Team Lead cum Consultant	Sona Koyo Steering Systems Ltd.
	12.2.6	OU Rollouts (5+) Upgrade from 12.2.4 to R12.2.6	Implementation Team Lead cum Finance Consultant	Genpact India Pvt. Ltd.
	12.2.4	Support	Finance Consultant	ATC India (Current)

Key Domain Engagements

Project Type	Client	Scope	Role
	HTL Ltd.	Internal Audit	Audit Manager
Company Audit	Isoft R&D India Pvt. Ltd.	Governance Risk & Compliance	Audit Manager
Company Audit	Financial Software & Systems Pvt. Ltd.	Design & Review of Internal Controls	Audit Manager
	Himachal Futuristics Communications Ltd.	Statutory Audit	Audit Lead
	Indian Bank	Concurrent Audit, ATM Audit, Revenue Audit, IS Audit	Audit Assistant
Bank Audit	Indian Overseas Bank	Concurrent Audit Stock Audit	Audit Assistant
	State Bank of Travancore (SBT)	Statutory Audit	Audit Manager
	ICICI Bank	Internal Audit Credit Card Audit	Audit Manager

Oracle Project Details

1.

Project Name ATC India Tower Corporation Pvt. Ltd.

Role Finance Functional Consultant

Project Type Finance Support

Modules Handled

GL, AP, FA, IExp and CM

Contribution

- Involved in daily Support of Oracle Applications Financial R12 General Ledger, Accounts Payable, Internet Expense,
 Cash Management & Fixed Assets.
- Issues analysis and resolution Understanding, documenting and providing solution to issues listed by the business users as per the SLA provided.
- Weekly business updates and interaction regarding issues raised and pending issues.
- Preparation of Weekly & Daily Dashboards of tickets raised and solution provided & discussion with Managers and IT
 Head.
- Smoke and regression testing of functionalities and processes on upgrade from R12.2.4 to R12.2.6.
- Preparation of SOPs for P2P and O2C Cycle and various FA Processes for end users and Business benefits
- Conducting training sessions for Business and End users to avoid the recurring issues
- Supported and guided on new Item masters creation and category assignment.
- Interacted with the Technical resource on daily basis to Design various MIS reports.
- Created MD-50 for form customization.
- Guided the Technical Resource to successfully create MD-70.

2

Project Name Religare Health Trust

Role Fusion Finance Functional Consultant

Project Type Implementation / Post Implementation Support

Modules

Handled AP, AR, GL, FA, CE

Contribution

- Client interaction for preparation of AS IS and TO BE documents.
- End to End implementation along with other Team Members and partner vendor.
- Worked on the following modules/ options Payables, Receivables, General Ledger, FA, Cash Management, EB-Tax.
- CRP, Business interaction and preparation of Process Manuals
- Post implementation support for the issues reported
- Looked into and resolved support issues with India Localization/ GST
- Implementation of India Localization Setups related to Excise, VAT, Service Tax and TDS and more recently GST

3.

Project Name Genpact India Pvt. Ltd.

Role Implementation Lead; Finance Functional Consultant

GST Implementation, Implementation Rollouts & Enhancements as per Business

Need

Modules Handled GL, AP, AR, IL, CE, PA, FA, INV, AGIS, EB Tax

Contribution

Project Type

• Created RD50 document, shared with business and taken signoff as an understanding of the Business requirement and sharing the proposed solution.

- Preparation of BR100 documents and BP 80 documents for the new business scenario.
- GST Implementation and mapping of various requirements as per India Localization.
- End to end rollouts Legal Entity creation > Ledger creation> OU and Inventory Orgs creation and carrying out the
 related setups of various modules. Modules worked include AP, AR, GL, FA, Project, AGIS, Cash Management, AGIS
 & EB Tax.
- Coordinated with users during UAT to resolve issues, prepared user manuals, CRP for new functionality & enhancements.
- Weekly Meetings with Division Heads to understand their problems in depth and provide solutions to improve business processes as well as Oracle Applications Functionality
- Auto Reconciliation functionality of Cash Management (Auto creation of AR Receipts and auto application to open AR invoices, Auto upload of MT940 & Auto Reconciliation)

4.

Project Name Sandhar Technologies Ltd.

Role Project Manager, Finance Functional Consultant

Project Type GL Consolidation

Modules Handled GL

Contribution

- Implementation of GL Consolidation
 - Preparation of Parent Ledger
 - COA Mapping
 - Mapping of Parent Ledger and Subsidiary Ledgers
- Mapping of manual Financial Statements in Rows and Columns of the FSG
- Preparation of Financial Statement from Oracle via FSG Reports
 - Balance Sheet and its Schedule
 - Profit and Loss Account and its Schedule
 - Cash Flow Statement
 - Schedule to Tangible Assets & Intangible Assets

Domain Project Details

1.

Project Name HTL Ltd.

Role Audit Manager
Project Type Internal Audit

Contribution

- Designing the audit program routines and execution of internal audit of the various Units independently.
- Preparation of internal audit report and follow-up for remediation
- Assisting team in conducting the special investigations
- Ensuring the Compliance with policies and rules
- Analysis of operations and proposing value-adding recommendations
- Identifying the weakness in the existing controls & processes and also provide evidential support

2.

Project Name Isoft R&D India Pvt. Ltd.

Role Audit Manager

Project Type Governance Risk & Compliance

Contribution

- Monitoring of controls for ensuring process compliance and detecting the control failures through Implementation
 of Uniform & Standard process of covering Enterprise Risk.
- Monitoring of the automated controls across processes on real time basis with the help of SAP GRC tool.
- Reporting of control deficiencies on real-time basis at global, cluster and country level.
- Analyzing the control deficiencies, preparing dashboards and writing reports for managerial presentations and review.
- Performing comparative analysis on the controls tested, deficiencies identified and deficiencies remediated to understand the control health of the company.
- Holding Control Health Meeting with the Control owners to agree remediation plans and driving Governance around timely remediation of issues and collation of audit evidences

3.

Project Name Financial Software & Systems Pvt. Ltd.

Role Audit Manager

Project Type Design and Review of Internal Controls

Contribution

- Understanding and streamlining the standard operating process and practices (SOPs)
- Performing Design Effectiveness Assessment (DEA) Detailed process / control walkthroughs Identifying design deficiencies and recommend remediation procedures
- Identifying and assessing the operating effectiveness of controls existing under each processes
- Identifying the areas of potential cost saving & reduction and suggesting measures to improve existing system
- Adherence to various legal, commercial and taxation laws, policies & practices
- Calculation and analysis of trends, variances and ratios
- Conducting Periodic physical verification of cash, stocks and fixed assets
- Analysis of debtors/creditors ageing, recovery period, balance confirmation procedures
- Drafting Internal Audit report & follow up for implementation

Project Name Indian Bank, Indian Overseas Bank, SBT, ICICI Bank

Role Audit Manager
Project Type Bank Audit

Contribution

- Concurrent, Internal & Statutory audit of various branches of Nationalized and Private Sector Banks
- Audit of processes, compliances and documentations in relation to loan disbursement to High Value Corporate Borrowers
- Site visit, stock check and confirmation of the drawling limit sanctioned to the borrowers
- Cross check of KYC compliances for various activities carried out (account opening, deposits creation, loan disbursement)
- Revenue Audit, Information System (IS) Audit, Audit of various high value loans as per RBI guidelines for early identification of NPAs and advise on the early measures to be taken.

References:

- 1. Mr. Chetan Juneja IT Head, ATC India
- 2. Mr. Vivek Grover AVP, IT at Genpact India Pvt. Ltd.
- 3. Mr. Sanjay Maindiratta GM-IT at Sandhar Technologies Limited
- 4. Mr. Deepak Pachaury Senior Manager IT Division at Honda Cars India Limited
- 5. Mr. Sri Hari Rao Chief Manager, Indian Bank, Roundtana Branch, Chennai

Personal Details

Permanent Address Biratnagar-04, Pokhariya, FIFA Marg, Nepal

Nationality Nepali

Languages Known English, Hindi and Nepali

Marital Status Married
Hobbies Music, Movies

RAJEEV POKHREL

Place: Gurgaon